54. Science fiction. What would happen if time travel became possible, or if robots developed real intelligence?
What if we discovered a new planet with a more advanced type of species?
These questions are the reason that science fiction exists. Science fiction takes possibilities like these and explores how human beings would react.
Science fiction, sci-fi, is fiction that takes place in a world that is somewhat like ours, but changed in important ways.
Those changes have to do with science and technology. But sci-fi is really interested in people, not just technology.
It tries to show how people, as we are now, would behave in strange new situations.
The literature of ideas is what science fiction is often called, because it goes beyond reality.
Science fiction is also called the literature of change. This is because it usually becomes popular in times of change.
When big changes are happening in a society, writers often try to explore them.
Sometimes the changes are too new or dangerous to write about. Science fiction writers, therefore, create metaphors.
They use their imaginary technological changes to represent real social changes or problems.
Science fiction was born in a time of change, the beginning of the age of reason in the West.
People's beliefs were being challenged by new scientific theories and developments.
Writers wanted to explore those changes. That era was when famous early sci-fi books like Gulliver's Travels were written.
Science fiction has been going strong since then. Some famous sci-fi writers are Isaac Asimov, Robert Heinlein, Philip K. Dick, H. G. Wells, and Ursula K. Le Guin, though there are many more.
If you like imagination and new ideas, sci-fi may be for you.